（美木杉(みきすぎ)）え… ええ…
え〜 待て 落ち着け 流子(りゅうこ)君
N-Now, now,
let's calm down, Ryuuko.
Don't give me that!
What the hell is going on?
（流子）うるせえ
どういうことなんだよ
Were you in cahoots with
that mohawked man too?
てめえも あのモヒカン男と
グルだったのか？
I-I have no idea what you mean.
な… 何の話かな？
Just try and play dumb
after you see this!
これを見ても とぼけられるか？
See? Here's you and the mohawked guy in the background, clear as day!
ほら この端に写ってるの
お前とあのモヒカン男だろ
—Th-That's not—
それ… それは…
After the mohawked guy attacked me, I asked Matarou to track him down.
（流子）
こないだ モヒカン男に
襲われたあと—
After the mohawked guy attacked me, I asked Matarou to track him down.
又郎(またろう)に頼んで
ヤツの行方を捜させたんだ
After the mohawked guy attacked me, I asked Matarou to track him down.
That kid has connections
all over this town.
あいつは この町じゃ
顔が広いからな
And he found pictures of a guy drinking booze who matched the description.
それらしい男が—
酒を飲んでるところが写ってる
写真を見つけてきたんだ
And he found pictures of a guy drinking booze who matched the description.
That also explains why
he brought me to your place.
あいつが ここに私を運んだのも
それで うなずける
He almost killed me, dammit!
So what the hell is your deal?!
（流子）こっちは生き死にの
瀬戸際だってのにどういうことだ！
And yet, wouldn't you say he brought you and Senketsu closer together?
だが 彼のおかげで君と鮮血(せんけつ)の
絆は深まった
His name is Kinagase Tsumugu.
I admit that he is a member of my organization.
彼の名は黄長瀬紬(きながせつむぐ)
確かに僕の組織の一員だ
After clashing in battle with him,
you and Senketsu have become true partners!
だが 彼との戦いの結果
君と鮮血は真の相棒になった
Now that Kiryuuin Satsuki
has her hands on a Godrobe,
鬼龍院皐月(きりゅういんさつき)が神衣(かむい)を手にした今
only a partnership forged in
the heat of battle can defeat her!
君が彼女に勝つためには
必要な試練だったのだ… うわっ
You're just tryin' to make up a
justification after the fact, aren't you?!
お前 今 無理やり正当化して
私を言いくるめようとしてるだろ？
（美木杉）ええ？
（流子）やっぱり そうか
I knew it!
That bastard tried to kill Senketsu!
Who are you people?!
あの野郎 鮮血を
殺そうとしやがった
お前ら 何者なんだよ
I thought you were fighting
against the Kiryuuins!
鬼龍院一派と
戦うんじゃなかったのか？
Didn't you say that you'd
need Senketsu to do that?
鮮血は そのための
力じゃないのかよ
What are those "Life Fiber" things, anyway?
大体“生命戦維(せんい)”
ってのは何なんだ？
What was my dad researching?!
父さんは何を研究してたんだ？
Calm down.
（美木杉）そう怒るな
Once I'm certain I can trust you,
I'll tell you everything.
君が信用できる人間だと
確信できれば全てを話す
I'm tired of hearing
that excuse from you!
（流子）
その言い訳は聞き飽きた
Nudist Beach.
（美木杉）ヌーディストビーチ
Huh?
We're Nudist Beach.
（美木杉）
我々は ヌーディストビーチだ
Have you lost it?
気は確かか？
It's the name of our
organization. Nudist Beach!
我々の組織の名だ
ヌーディストビ〜チ！
Forget it. I was stupid to think I could expect a straight answer out of you.
（流子）もういい
あんたに真面目なことを
聞こうとした私がバカだった
Ryuuko?
（美木杉）あっ 流子君？
Fine, I get it! I'll keep fighting
and growing stronger.
わかったよ
もっと戦って
もっと強くなる
That's what you want, right?
それで いいんだろ？
But that really is our name.
ホントの名前なのに…
ま 結果オーライか
Oh well, it worked out in the end.
EPISODE 6
DON'T TOY WITH ME ON A WHIM
This is a world tailored to someone's whims and fancies
dareka ga katteni kimeta readymade na
I'll break free of its shackles
kyou wo nugisutete
RYUUKO
MATOI
And sprint toward my goal
hadashi de hashitte iku
Even if I lose my way
machigattatte
GAMAGOORI IRA
SANAGEYAMA UZU
JAKUZURE NONON
INUMUTA HOUKA
Or trip and fall
korondatte
INUMUTA HOUKA
MANKANSHOKU FAMILY
MANKANSHOKU
MAKO
Those wounds will still create
surimuita itami mo
MANKANSHOKU
MAKO
MIKISUGI
AIKUROU
KINAGASE
TSUMUGU
An original future for me
original na ashita ni naru
KIRYUUIN
SATSUKI
I hold my destiny in my own hands
tsukiageta kono te ni nigirishimeta
And it shines ever so brightly
chikai ga hikari ni natte
So until the day I reach you
itsuka kimi ni todoku sono shunkan made
I don't have the time to sit around crying
naiteru hima nante nai kara
My burning passion pours out from within me
hamidashite shimatta atsui omoi ga
And shines like a star in the night sky
yozora de kagayaki dasu
I think I now understand
umarete kita imi ga
Why I was born
wakatta ki ga shita
I'll make all of my dreams come true
negaigoto wa zenbu kono te de
With my own hands
kanaeru
SEWING CLUB RESEARCH LAB
UNDERGROUND PARKING LOT
Okay. Load the Life Fibers into the vault.
（伊織(いおり)）
よし 生命戦維を
保管庫に運び入れろ
SEWING
CLUB
PRESIDENT
IORI SHIROU
I wonder what Lady Satsuki intends to do with so many Life Fibers?
（猿投山(さなげやま)）これだけの生命戦維—
どうするつもりなんだろうな
皐月様は
She means to mass-produce
Ultima Uniforms.
極(ごく)制服の大量生産だよ
ほかに使い道があるか
What else could they be for?
LIFE
FIBER
But every time we've proposed increasing the number of Two-Star Ultima Uniforms to bolster our ranks,
（猿投山）今まで
二つ星極制服を増やして—
戦力を増強させようと
俺たちが提案しても—
かたくなに拒んできたのは
あの人だったじゃないか
she personally vetoed the suggestion.
部長の粗製乱造は—
If we focus on increasing the quantity of
club presidents, we risk lowering the overall quality.
質の低下を招く可能性があるのは
事実だからな
That was Lady Satsuki's primary concern.
皐月様は それを憂慮されていた
However, she has deemed it necessary to increase the club president head count despite the risks.
（犬牟田(いぬむた)）
だが それを踏まえても—
部長を増やす必要があると
考えられた
I guess this means that Matoi Ryuuko's arrival has set things into motion in a big way.
纏(まとい)流子の出現で—
局面が大きく動きだした
ということだな
Yeah. In fact, the Anti-Uniform Guerilla himself showed up the other day.
（猿投山）ああ この間は
反制服ゲリラまで現れたしな
And the clincher is that Lady Satsuki has chosen to don a Godrobe herself.
（伊織）何より 皐月様ご自身が
神衣に袖を通された
I'm amazed that there are even two people out there who can handle a uniform made entirely of Life Fibers.
（犬牟田）
生命戦維100パーセントの服
それを着こなす人間が２人もいる
To be frank, I have trouble believing it.
僕には信じられないよ
Wow! There's something out there that not even Inumuta, Intelligence and Tactics Officer, can believe?
へえ 情報部長の犬牟田さんにも
信じられないことがあるのか
（犬牟田）
信じられないことだらけだ
だから この学園は面白い
It's just one unbelievable
thing after another, really.
That's what makes this
academy so fascinating.
Ah, I see.
なるほど
Personally, I came here because I heard
that I'd be able to fight with my full strength.
俺は俺の力が存分に振るえる
と聞いてここに来た
That Matoi is worthy of
my complete attention.
あの纏なら
俺の力の振るいがいがある
（エレベーターの
停止音）
Hold on, Sanageyama.
（犬牟田）待てよ 猿投山
Have you forgotten that Lady Satsuki ordered us Four Devas to simply stand by and watch?
四天王は しばらく様子を見ていろ
という皐月様の命令を忘れたのか？
Oh? Did she really say that?
（猿投山）はあ？ そうだったっけ
It is rather draining, isn't it?
（皐月）さすがに こたえるか
Please try not to
overexert yourself, milady.
（揃(そろい)）あまり
ご無理をなさりませんよう
Don't worry. This is the path I chose.
案ずるな 私が選んだ道だ
Your tea warms me
through and through, Soroi.
しみるな 揃のお茶は
（揃）ありがとうございます
Thank you, milady.
（皐月）
私の後ろを取ったつもりかな？
猿投山
Did you think you'd managed to get behind me, Sanageyama?
Of course not.
とんでもない 俺がちょっとでも
襲う気になったら—
If I'd had the slightest intent to attack,
you could have easily killed me with just that teacup.
そのティーカップ１つで
こっちの息の根が止められますよ
（皐月）だったら何の用だ？
（猿投山）纏と戦わせてくれ
What do you want, then?
Allow me to fight Matoi.
Why?
（皐月）なぜ？
Need you even ask?
その問いは やぼですよ
俺が強いヤツを見るとどうなるか
皐月様もよくご存じのはずだ
I believe you know perfectly well what happens whenever I catch sight of someone powerful.
Just like three years ago, then?
３年前のようにか？
THREE YEARS AGO
NORTHERN KANTO, SUSUKIGAHARA
（犬牟田）１対500か
One against five hundred, eh?
This will prove once and for all whether Kiryuuin Satsuki is fit to lead us.
これで 鬼龍院皐月が—
本当に我々の盟主にふさわしいか
はっきりする
（蛇崩(じゃくずれ)）
だったら早めに頭を下げる準備を
しといたほうがいいわ
I suggest you start
practicing your bow, then.
（蟇郡(がまごおり)）うむ
I'm Sanageyama Uzu, Northern Kanto Gang Leader Alliance Representative!
北関東番長連合総代 猿投山渦(うず)だ
MIDDLE
SCHOOL
THIRD
YEAR
NORTHERN KANTO GANG LEADER
ALLIANCE REPRESENTATIVE SANAGEYAMA UZU
You've got guts, Kiryuuin,
picking a fight with me!
この俺にケンカを
ふっかけるとは—
いい度胸だな 鬼龍院
I have no intention of fighting you.
（皐月）ケンカなど
するつもりはない
I expect you to surrender.
MIDDLE
SCHOOL
THIRD
YEAR
KIRYUUIN SATSUKI
軍門に下れと
言っているのだ
Who do you think you're screwin' with?!
（番長）
なめんじゃねえぜ こら〜！
（皐月）喝！
（番長たち）うわ〜
You stopped them
with just your spirit, huh?
気合いで止めるか 上等だ
だが 俺には効かねえよ！
But that won't work on me!
I've seen through your moves!
てめえの動きは見切った！
You're mine!
もらった！
Did you think you'd
managed to get behind me?
（皐月）
それで私の後ろを取ったつもりか？
Come.
（皐月）来い
I'll provide you with the ultimate stage
—where you can unleash your full strength—
お前が力を振るえる最高の舞台を
用意してやる
the stage called Honnouji Academy.
本能字(ほんのうじ)学園という舞台をな
My bamboo sword is itching to test out the skills of this girl
（猿投山）
あなたが用意してくれた—
この舞台に紛れ込んできた女が
どれほどのものか—
who managed to infiltrate
the stage you provided for me.
俺の竹刀が試したいと
うずいているんですがね
I trust you understand
the price of failure?
（皐月）負ければ
どうなるか わかっているな？
Not to worry.
（猿投山）ご心配なく
With these eyes, I can't possibly lose.
俺にはこの目がある
負けるわけがない
Nicely blocked.
よく かわした
なんとか 中学生のあなたなら
勝てるようになりましたよ
I've managed to grow strong enough to
defeat your middle-school self in battle.
That was the way you
moved three years ago.
今のは３年前のあなたの動きだ
本当は そんなものじゃないでしょ
I assume you were holding back.
Very well. See what you can do.
いいだろう やってみろ
Thanks. I appreciate it.
（猿投山）どうも 感謝します
勝ったら お茶でも
ごちそうしてください
If I win, treat me to tea or something.
（皐月）不作法をしたな 揃
I've done you a discourtesy, Soroi.
Not at all, milady, though I do find it
a shame. That was your favorite cup.
（揃）いえ ただ—
お嬢様のお気に入りの
カップだったので残念です
Make a fresh pot for me.
新しいお茶をいれてくれ
Certainly, milady.
（揃）かしこまりました
（受話器を取る音）
（揃）はい
Hello. You have reached the Honnouji Academy Student Council President's Office.
（揃）本能字学園
生徒会長室でございます
Y-Yes, ma'am. One moment, ma'am.
あっ はい 少々お待ちください
It is Mistress Ragyou.
羅暁(らぎょう)様でございます
This is Satsuki.
皐月です
What's this I hear about you
putting on your wedding dress?
（羅暁）
花嫁衣装に袖を通したそうだね
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
Challenge To A Duel
Attention, Matoi Ryuuko of Class 2-A:
I will be waiting in the
Kendo Club dojo after school.
— Sanageyama Uzu
SPORTS
GYM #1
That wild monkey
beat us to the punch.
（蛇崩）
あの山猿ったら抜け駆けを
手を出して
いいんだったら
If I'd gotten permission to make a move on her, I would've taken her out first.
あたしが先に
やっちゃったのに
（犬牟田）皐月様は？
Where is Lady Satsuki?
She has gone out.
（蟇郡）お出かけになった
She said this battle
was not worth watching.
“この戦いは見るまでもない”と
（蛇崩）何？ それ
What's that supposed to mean?
（歓声）
（猿投山）来たな 纏
So you've come, Matoi.
I was summoned by name
by one of the Four Devas.
四天王 じきじきのご指名だ
逃げるわけにはいかないだろ
How could I run away
after such an invitation?
いい心掛けだ
とっとと始めようぜ！
I like your spirit!
Let's get right to it!
（猿投山）三つ星極制服…
Three-Star Ultima Uniform: Blade Regalia!
THREE
STAR
ULTIMA
UNIFORM
BLADE REGALIA
It's not just the Godrobes
that can transform!
（猿投山）変身は神衣だけの
お家芸じゃないってことだ！
へえ やるねえ 四天王
じゃあ こっちも
I'm impressed, Deva!
Time for me to follow suit!
Life Fiber Synchronize, Godrobe Senketsu!
人衣(じんい)一体 神衣鮮血！
GODROBE
SENKETSU
...Why, you...
この〜！
I can read all your moves!
（猿投山）
お前の動きは全て見える！
（流子）鮮血 スピードを上げるぞ
（鮮血）わかった
Senketsu! I'm going full speed!
Understood!
—What the—
何！ あっ
Ow!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
（猿投山）
どんなに お前が速く動こうと
俺の剣から逃れることはできない！
No matter how quickly you move, you can't outrun my blade!
Behold! Secret Technique: Heaven's Eye!
見よ！
秘技 天眼通(てんがんつう)！
HEAVEN'S
EYE
As long as I have these eyes, I can
anticipate any move my opponent makes!
この目があるかぎり
相手がどう動くのか 全て読める！
Say what?!
（流子）何だと
For every motion a human makes, there is a preparatory motion.
（犬牟田）
人間が行動を
起こす前には—
必ず 予備動作がある
ORBICULARIS
OCULI
Be it a movement of the eyes
or a twitch of the muscles,
目の動き 筋肉の動き
DORSAL
INTEROSSEOUS
ADDUCTOR
POLLICIS
Sanageyama instantly reads
all of those preparatory motions
猿投山は その全ての
予備動作を—
PECTORALIS
MAJOR
GLUTEUS
MAXIMUS
瞬時に読み取り
相手の行動の先手を取る
and pre-empts any move
his opponent attempts to make.
That is the power of the Heaven's Eye.
それが天眼通だ
And his Ultima Uniform succeeds
magnificently in amplifying that ability.
見事に彼の極制服も
その能力の拡大に成功している
へえ 山猿さん 腕を上げたわね
Gosh, Mr. Wild Monkey has
learned some new tricks, hasn't he?
Is that what Lady Satsuki meant when she
...said this fight was not worth watching? But...
皐月様が“見るまでもない”と
言ったのは このことか だが…
I didn't hear it that way at all.
そうは聞こえなかったと？
（蟇郡）ふむ
Keep it together, Ryuuko!
（鮮血）しっかりしろ 流子
（流子）
うう… しっかりしたいのは
やまやまだが—
I'd love to, but it's all I can do just to deflect these strikes!
かわすのが精いっぱいだ
I'm impressed!
（猿投山）やるな…
だが これなら どうだ！
But let's see how you handle... this!
God-Speed Thousand Thrusts!
神速(しんそく)千本突き！
Now I can read all your
attempts to block me, too!
（猿投山）お前の受けの動きも
全て読めている
Even your Ultima Uniform-destroying
Sword Scissor is worthless if it can't hit its target!
極制服を切り裂く
片太刀バサミも—
当たらなければ
どうと言うことはない！
Come on, is that all you've got?
（猿投山）
おいおい これで終わりか？
ずいぶん あっけないじゃないか
A little disappointing, don't you think?
ん？ そう こなくっちゃな
That's more like it!
Senketsu. I have a favor to ask of you.
鮮血 お前にひとつ頼みがある
I understand. Bet it all on
a single roll of the dice, eh?
（鮮血）わかった １回勝負だな
（マコ）流子ちゃん！
（猿投山）もらった！
Ryuuko!
You're mine!
と… 取れない！
T-They won't come off!
M-My eyes!
目… 目が！
Now!
今だ！
Finishing Move: Thread Stripper!
必殺 戦維喪失！
"STRIPPED"
OF THE
WILL
TO FIGHT!
Oh, dear. He went and lost.
（蛇崩）あ〜らら
負けちゃった
It would appear that this is what Lady Satsuki was referring to.
（犬牟田）
どうやら 皐月様のお言葉は
こういうことだったらしい
You did it, Ryuuko!
やったね 流子ちゃん
もう 四天王を倒すなんて—
You beat one of the Four Devas already!
すごいよ 早いよ かっこいいよ〜
うん うん！
You're amazing! And so fast!
And so awesome! Yeah!
This isn't over yet!
まだ終わっちゃいねえ！
俺はまだ戦える 来い 纏！
I can still fight! Come on, Matoi!
うっ ひっ ぎゃあ
Don't be pathetic, Sanageyama!
見苦しいぞ 猿投山！
You have disgraced the Four Devas!
四天王の恥を知れ！
One who over-relies on a single skill will be brought low by that very same skill, huh?
一芸に頼る者は 一芸に滅ぶ か…
BACK-ALLEY DOCTOR
MANKANSHOKU
あ〜 効くな〜
Ah, that hits the spot.
（流子）気持ちいいのか？
（鮮血）ああ アイロンは いい
It feels good?
Yes, irons are wonderful.
体のしわというしわが伸びて—
It feels like all the wrinkles in my body are
melting away as my Life Fibers line up one by one.
戦維１本１本に
ぴしっと芯が通る感じだ
作戦どおり猿投山の目隠しが
うまくいってよかった
I'm glad my plan for you to
blind Sanageyama worked.
切られたのは結構 痛かったぞ
Being cut up was rather
painful, I'll have you know.
Sorry about that.
（流子）悪かった
（鮮血）気にするな
Don't worry about it.
If we hadn't won, I wouldn't be enjoying this pleasant ironing.
勝たなければ こうして
アイロンも かけてもらえない
True.
And make sure to get
behind my lapels, too.
襟の裏のほうも よくかけてくれ
丁寧にな
Be thorough about it.
Man, you're one demanding
article of clothing, you know that?
（流子）
注文の多い服だな ったく
Ryuuko's mumbling
to her uniform again.
（又郎）流子の姉御
また 服相手にぶつぶつ言ってるよ
I think it's fine.
いいのよ あれで
Who's there?!
（伊織）誰だ？
Iori, I have a favor to ask of you.
伊織 お前に頼みがある
（揃）
お母様のご機嫌はいかがでした？
How was your mother's disposition?
I explained to her
why I took out Junketsu.
純潔を持ち出した理由は説明した
You needn't worry, Soroi.
揃が心配することはない ん？
I've no time for losers, Sanageyama.
負け犬に用はないぞ 猿投山
（猿投山）
俺は自分の目に慢心していた
もう一度 チャンスを
I was overconfident in my eyesight.
Please give me one more chance!
I'll defeat Matoi for certain next time!
今度こそ必ず纏を倒す！
Pathetic.
（皐月）惨めな
I don't need subordinates
who lack resolve.
覚悟なき者は私の部下にいらぬ
But resolve I have,
（猿投山）
覚悟ならある このとおり！
and here is my proof!
ほう
Challenge
HONNOUJIGAHARA
（流子）一度 負けた人間に
もう一度チャンスを与えるとは—
Giving someone who was
beaten a second chance?
ずいぶんと甘いもんだな
鬼龍院皐月
You're a soft touch, Kiryuuin Satsuki.
Let's see how soft you think I am after the fight, Matoi Ryuuko.
甘いかどうかは戦ってから言え
纏流子
Observe what happens
when you force a man to change.
〝男子三日会わざれば
刮目(かつもく)して見よ〞
（猿投山）
三つ星極制服 剣(つるぎ)の装 改(あらため)
Three-Star Ultima Uniform:
Blade Regalia Mk 2!
THREE
STAR
ULTIMA
UNIFORM
BLADE REGALIA
MK 2
（鮮血）気を付けろ 流子
前回とは雰囲気が違うぞ
Be careful, Ryuuko.
I'm getting a totally
different vibe to last time.
Let's work fast, then.
だったら先手必勝だ
Life Fiber Synchronize, Godrobe Senketsu!
人衣一体 神衣鮮血！
GODROBE
SENKETSU
Sorry about this, Senketsu.
ごめんな 鮮血
I've covered up every last eye you've got!
（流子）今度は体中の目を塞いだ
Now you can't use your Heaven's Eye!
これで天眼通は使えねえ！
（流子）うっ うう…
（鮮血）見ろ！ 流子
Look, Ryuuko!
His eyes are shut!
（流子）目が潰れてる！
Iori, I want you to sew my eyes shut.
伊織 この目を縫ってくれ
But if I did that,
you'd lose your Heaven's Eye!
しかし それでは君は
天眼通を失うことになる
That's all right.
かまわねえ 負けた原因は
俺の慢心だ
I lost due to my own overconfidence.
Unless my eyes are sewn shut,
I can never beat Matoi!
この目を封じなきゃ
纏に勝つことはできねえ！
This is the resolve of a man who has realized
the error of his ways and sacrificed everything!
自らの過ちを悟り
全てを捨てた男の覚悟だ
心して かかれよ 纏！
Know that as you face him, Matoi!
Here I come.
（猿投山）参る
ハァ ハァ 何だ？ この迫力は
What is this intimidating aura?
Head!
（猿投山）面！ 胴！ 小手(こて)！
Body!
Wrist!
Oh, crap! These aren't the moves of someone with no eyes!
まいったな 目が見えないヤツの
動きじゃねえぞ
You're terrified, aren't you, Matoi?
（猿投山）おびえているな 纏
Say what?!
何だと！ おわっ
The sound of your breathing.
（猿投山）お前の息遣い 汗の臭い
The smell of your sweat.
I can see the inner workings
of your mind as clear as day.
お前の心の動きが
手に取るようにわかるぞ
ああ 目で見ていたよりも
はるかに はっきりとわかる
I can see it far, far more clearly than I could with my eyes!
この世界の全てがな！
Everything about this world!
The Mind's Eye.
心眼通(しんがんつう) 心の目だ
Sealing his eyes shut boosted his affinity with his Ultima Uniform.
（皐月）視覚を封じた分
極制服との親和性が強まっている
（猿投山）
面 胴 小手！ 面 胴 小手！
Head! Body! Wrist!
今や 極制服が猿投山の
目であり 鼻であり 耳だ
That Ultima Uniform is now
Sanageyama's eyes! His nose! His ears!
Head! Body! Wrist!
（猿投山）
面 胴 小手！
He has acquired the Mind's Eye,
which surpasses even the Heaven's Eye.
（皐月）
天眼通を超える心眼通を会得した
（猿投山）
面 胴 小手！
MIND'S EYE
None can evade his attacks!
ヤツの攻撃から
逃れる者はいない！
Head! Body! Wrist!
（猿投山）面！
（流子）ああっ
（猿投山）胴！ 小手！
Head! Body! Wrist!
面 胴 小手！
（猿投山）面 胴 小手！
（流子）うわあ〜
Without your weapon, you have
no means of turning the tables this time.
得物(えもの)をなくしたお前に
逆転のすべはない
そう思うだろ…
So you'd think, right?
何！
—What the—
I thought I told you that
I could see the entire world.
（猿投山）
世界の全てが見えると言ったはずだ
貴様のこそくな手が通用すると
思ったか！
Did you think your pathetic
little trick would work?
Head!
（猿投山）面！
（流子）あうっ
（猿投山）胴！ 小手！
（流子）うあっ
Body! Wrist!
Head! Body! Wrist!
（猿投山）
面 胴 小手！ 面 胴 小手！
面 胴 小手！ 面 胴 小手！…
Head!
（猿投山）面！
（流子）うわ〜 ぐうっ
（流子）ゴホッ ゴ…
It's all over.
（猿投山）終わりだ
—It's—
あれは！
What?!
（猿投山）何？
What? What happened?
何だ？ 何が起こった？
The Ultima Uniform overheated!
（伊織）
極制服がオーバーヒートした
（皐月）恥じるな！ 猿投山
This was no disgrace, Sanageyama.
お前の力が極制服を凌駕(りょうが)した結果だ
It was the result of your own power
outstripping that of the Ultima Uniform.
Yes, ma'am.
（猿投山）はい
（流子の息遣い）
（皐月）纏め 命拾いしたな
Matoi, you got lucky this time.
（流子）ハァハァハァ…
（鮮血）危ないところだったな
That was a close call.
ああ 本能字四天王は
ダテじゃねえか
Yes, I guess the Four Devas
of Honnouji aren't all show.
That guy was seriously tough.
さすがに手ごわいな
だが 逃げ出すわけにはいかねえ
But I can't run away from this.
私は父さんの死の秘密を
知らなきゃならない
I have to learn the truth
behind Dad's death!
I swapped out the Life Fibers in
your Ultima Uniform and restitched it.
（伊織）君の極制服の生命戦維を
入れ替えて再縫製した
これで 君の動きにも
ついていけるはずだ
It should be able to keep up
with even your movements now.
Thanks.
Did you think you'd managed to get behind me, Sanageyama?
私の後ろを取ったつもりか？
猿投山
Front and behind
mean nothing to me now.
（猿投山）今の俺には
前も後ろも関係ありません
目が潰れたおかげで
逆に 世界の全てを感じられますよ
Now that my eyes have been sewn shut, I can sense the world in its entirety.
新しいきっかけを
つくってくれたあなたに—
I only came to thank you
for giving me a fresh start.
お礼を言いに来ただけです
Wait.
（皐月）待て
約束だ 茶を振る舞おう
We had an agreement.
Let's have tea.
Thank you, but I'll pass.
（猿投山）いいえ 遠慮しときます
My other senses have become so heightened that my tongue can no longer bear the heat.
ほかの感覚が鋭くなり過ぎて—
猫舌になっちまったんですよ
Before the bell rings
chime ga naru mae ni
I sneak out of school
kugurinuketa
Avoiding the adults' vacant stares
otonatachi no haiiro no me
The pointless conversations
tawai no nai kaiwa
Keep going on and on
togirenu mama
As I walk down the slope
sakamichi wo kudatteku
I have nothing to do
nani wo suru demo naku
And nowhere to go
yuku ate sae mo naku
Right now, all I do
tada atashi ima wa ne
Is ignore any and all warnings
donna chuukoku mo mimi wo surinukeru
Because I still want to be free
mada mada suki ni sasete
I'm sorry, but it's not like me
gomen ne e ni kaita you na
To be an exemplary student
yuutosei wa rashiku nai wa
So I undo two of my shirt buttons
shirt no button wo futatsu hazushite
And take the back alley
rojiura no nukemichi
A path of mysterious sweet temptation
amai yuuwaku wa michi
Some things I've kept hidden from everyone
dare ni mo mada hanashite nai
But tonight, I will reveal my secrets to you
atashi no himitsu wo kon'ya oshiete ageru
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
（鮮血）
満艦飾(まんかんしょく)家が夢を見た
The Mankanshoku family had a dream.
六畳一間に家族４人
犬１匹 居候１人
Four people in a one-room house,
along with a dog and a freeloader.
FAMILY
DOG
A FREELOADER
貧乏暮らしに慣れた身が
なぜか突然ぜいたく暮らし
POOR
This poor family suddenly find
themselves living in the lap of luxury!
LUXURY
頂点 目指して 有頂天
TOP
Walk on air as you aim for the top!
WALK ON AIR
次回 キルラキル
「憎みきれない ろくでなし」
Next time on KILL la KILL,
"A Loser I Can't Hate".
EPISODE 7
A LOSER I
CAN'T HATE